to give you another perspective on the
journey that you and I are about to go
through. I wanted to share something
that was written by Steve Yaggi, the
author of a of a product called Guest
Town. That's that's that's huge that
that that we will look at at some point.
And it's this this has been a very
popular post when he described the
different stages that you go through as
an AI coder as you use AI in a more and
more advanced way. So in his post, Steve
described the first stage of your AI
journey is using things like interacting
with chat GBT and using AI autocomplete
to help you code just as something that
you refer over to. Stage two is when you
have a coding agent and it's in the
sidebar of your IDE just as it was for
us with cursor moments ago, but it's
asking for permission before it makes
any change to the code. you are checking
everything step by step and it's just
there to give you suggestions maybe to
make a few changes with your with your
approval with your express consent and
then stage three is the same except you
are now in something that we like to
call yolo mode yolo of course sure you
only live once uh but this is the mode
where you just don't accept changes you
just say I accept everything go for it
do do whatever you want I trust you it's
a level of trust that you're giving the
coding agent in the IDE sidebar and
Steve also distinguished between a stage
four which is where it's it's more of a
sort of conceptual change where you
don't have the coding agent in a sidebar
but it's really occupying the main
window you've kind of expanded it and as
far as you're concerned that is where
you're looking you're not looking at the
code that it's changing you're looking
at the agent of what it's telling you
and occasionally you're checking the
differences in code that it's making.
You're seeing them fly by. You're not
actually expressly accepting them.
You're just seeing them, looking at
them, but maybe you're just walking away
and letting it do its thing. That is the
distinction between stage three and
stage four. Stage four, your attention
is on the agent, not on the code. Now,
all of stages one to four were about
working in an IDE like cursor or VS
Code. Stage five is where you've moved
to the command line, to the CLI, to the
terminal. you're using clawed code or
similar a coding agent in the CLI.
You're still on YOLO letting it do its
thing and now the diffs are just
scrolling by. You're not even checking
them. You're just sitting back watching
it happen. Maybe you're just leaving it
as I say coming back later and it's
done. That's stage five. And stage six
is the same except it's not one agent
now. You've spawned multiple agents.
you've got many of them working
concurrently on your project like you've
got a little team maybe three to five
agents and they're all running in your
CLI. Okay. And then seven is just upping
the ante. You've now got 10 or more
agents in your CLI and you're managing
them all yourself. You're like kicking
them all off and watching them do their
thing and coordinating what they're all
doing. So, it's like you're you've got a
lot of work to do to to coordinate them
and they're all running. It's like
you're hugely leveraged with all of
these agents and sub agents all running,
building your stuff for you. And of
course, you see where this is heading.
Stage eight is when you have an agent
that is orchestrating the other agents.
So, you're not manually managing this.
You've got agents managing each other.
And maybe there's a whole hierarchy.
There's one agent managing a bunch of
manager agents that are all managing a
bunch of worker agents all in some
structured way. There's a testing team,
a design team. There's all sorts of
different roles and responsibilities
happening in your agents orchestrating
other agents. That is stage eight. That
is the most advanced stage in Steve's
progression. And in Steve's original
post, he also asked Google Gemini's Nano
Banana to come up with images associated
with each one. And this these are like
the little nanobanana images. And you
can see they tell that story of the
progression particularly figure eight on
the bottom right. You can really see
that sense of hierarchy and of many
agents that are organized together and
coordinating activities. That is the
journey. And I'll just make the point
that week one of our course here is
about those first four stages. Not
really stage one because that's just
using chat GPT. I imagine you can do
that already. It's really stages 2,
three, and four. We're going to be
covering that in the first week. The
second week is all about stage five.
We're really digging down on stage five
to make sure that's absolutely
understood. And then very much the third
week is about adding six, seven and
eight to the mix so that we end up at
the the the very peak performance using
an entire orchestrated network of agents
to deliver your product. And I'll make
the point that whilst these eight stages
represent moving to more and more
sophisticated use of AI to build more
and more, it's not necessarily it
doesn't necessarily translate to to the
most advanced way to use AI agents in
the enterprise. In fact, I would argue
that somewhere between stages five and
six is the sweet spot for building
quality software in the enterprise. And
that is mostly what we will be focused
on in this course. It is largely stage
five in week two and stage six in week
three. I'm going to be giving you stages
seven and eight so you can see it
happening. Whether you would actually
use that in practice in the enterprise
at least today I would say is an open
question. But certainly you will have
exposure to it. But five and six is
really for me the sweet spot for
building bulletproof reliable scalable
software and adding the most commercial
value. Okay. Now, you and I at this
point have to have a conversation about
AI costs. Always a hot topic. I get a
bunch of questions on this every single
day. And so, let me let me set the
record straight. Let's have words on
this. So, look, here's the thing. You
can take this entire course without
spending a penny on API costs. Not a
scent. You don't need to spend anything.
You can also, should you wish, consume a
lot of your of your money. There's
plenty of opportunity uh to spend plenty
on Claude Code and others. It's a it's
an easy way to burn lots of money if you
want to ramp up and have 20 agents build
something enormous. Certainly, they will
happily take your money. So, that option
is available for you. I often do and I
have great fun. And for me, it's worth
it. But it's it's your choice and you
should always understand what you're
going to spend and make sure that that
is worth it to you. My recommendation I
think to get the most out of this course
is to just have the cursor pilot as long
as you you still are eligible for that
free period. Uh just so that you've had
some experience with it and then go for
the $20 a month plan with Claude Code
which is where we'll spend weeks two and
three and only go up beyond that if you
want to get more intense. So that would
be my recommendation, but it's not like
it's required. You don't need to spend a
scent. If you choose to not spend
anything, if that's if that's how you'd
like to approach this, please look at
the resources where I'll try and put in
extra uh tips and examples for how you
do it, how you set up to use uh free
models. And there will be some parts of
the course that you might need to skip
some things that I'll show you that that
are paid products. in which case, just
take it that I'm showing it to you for
future reference, and you won't use that
yourself, but you'll use one of the free
tools instead. So, you may need to pick
and choose as we go a little bit. I'll
try and put notes about that in the
resources and keep an eye on that. And
so, for the golden rule, the golden
rule, it is this. It is that I I will
take responsibility for many things on
this course. I am responsible for
getting you to be able to to answer the
Andre tweet at the end of 3 weeks, but I
can't take responsibility for the API
costs, the the AI costs. You need to
make the decisions about the spend
you're comfortable with, and you need to
monitor any costs that you're incurring
on the different platforms. I'll be very
clear on how you do it and where you do
it as we go. But that part of it, it
needs to be on you. I'm I'm sherking
that responsibility because I can't have
that responsibility. It's pricing. It
varies depending your different regions.
There are different offers available for
people. There are various free trials.
There are special deals and and and I
don't know about them. You will need to
do that research and make sure that
you're comfortable with whatever you
sign up for. So, this is the one thing
I'll give you as much transparency and
clarity as I possibly can. But please,
you you need to be in the driving seat
when it comes to AI costs. And I know
this is a source of frustration for
people because it feels like you're
getting nickel and dimeed when
everything you sign up for is like
another $20 a month or whatever, but
it's just worth keeping in mind that
this is the the new cost of working with
this kind of technology. We're all
familiar with the model that you might
need to buy a laptop that might cost as
much as $1,000 or or more for high-end
laptops. And that doesn't surprise us,
but this this sort of $20, $30 a month
from lots of different people, that's
something which we're not used to. And
so it feels like there's there's
friction and it's painful. But keep in
mind that these vendors do it doing this
kind of AI calculation involves hundreds
of trillions of floatingpoint
calculations. There's a lot of compute
that goes into it. And someone needs to
pay the electricity bills. They can't
lose money on doing this for you. And
and as I say, it's a it's it's
astonishing that we're able to have AIs
that can do what they can do. And so it
shouldn't be massively shocking that
there is some some cost associated with
it. So for what it's worth, I will say
that I do want to make the point again.
You you're in charge of your charges. Uh
you're you're the boss. You're in charge
of that, but I'm here to help. So if you
ever have any questions, ask me at any
time. I'll give you all the information
I can. I'll show you where to look. So,
as long as you're you're happy to be in
control of those costs, uh I'm here to
make sure that they are as transparent
as possible.